J +44 7397128043

github.com/ketanrajpal
in linkedin.com/in/ketanrajpal/

≡ SUMMARY.

A robust leader, having more than **9-years** of experience in designing, architecting and supporting enterprise-level internet-scale services/solutions hosted on cloud and On-premises. Familiarity with a relevant and globally supported framework, both **front-end** and **back-end**; thorough understanding of **user experience** and possibly even product strategy. Gained accreditation while working with **60+ clients**, Ministry of External Affairs (India), T-Series, Connexons Travel, Tomatinos Pizzeria and Taperia Tapas Food Chain in London, NYC Airports Limo (Taxi Chain in various towns in the US).

TECHNICAL SKILLS.

→ Front-end HTML5, Javascript, CSS3, SCSS, JQuery, React JS, Bootstrap, and Material UI

→ Back-end Typescript, Node JS, Python, GraphQL, and PHP

Framework & Database Django, Flask, PostgreSQL, Express JS, Mongo DB, MySql, and Sqlite

→ Deployment AWS (EC2, Amplify, Lambda, Elastic Beanstalk), Serverless, Firebase and Google Cloud

Testing frameworks Mocha, Jest, Chai, and Supertest

Designing User Experience Journeys, Prototyping & Wireframing, and Adobe (XD, InDesign, Photoshop)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE.

→ LONDON SCHOOL OF COMMERCE (JULY 2013 - PRESENT)

DESIGNATION: FULL STACK DEVELOPER (WEB DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER)

- Single-handedly performed various tasks of architecting, developing, and improving digital platforms for all the LSC Group of Colleges across London, Malta, Malaysia, Colombo, and Dhaka by completing end to end responsibility for design, layout, coding, deploying, managing, and maintaining all the corporate websites, application forms, student portals, and student management systems.
- Developed strategies for the admissions department to meet the company's goals and objectives and to improve the quality of the service it delivers internally and externally.
- Successfully developed interview feedback and appointment system that improved interviewers productivity and also saved a ton of time.
- Created automated student management and assessment systems on top of 3rd party API's to deliver 5000+ lectures online across the Globe.
- Ability to handle highly stressed situations and unexpected errors in an efficient manner.
- Managing responsibility for all the web operations (WebOps) from deploying, maintaining all the digital assets of the group, creating the Online Student Learning Platform, Live Virtual Classrooms and Online Assessment Systems.
- Improve the performance of existing applications.
- Stellar in deploying applications on AWS EC2, Lambda, S3, Elastic Beanstalk, Digital Ocean Containers and 1&1 Cloud. Acted as a single point of contact for managing the group web servers and monitoring performance.
- Conducting market research and analytics to generate a maximum inflow of students. Creating advertising and promotional materials for distribution like flyers, brochures and adverts for online and print.
- Profitably upheld branding strategies for UK universities.
- Essayed a key role in handling updates and maintenance of all the social media platforms like Facebook, Twitter, Google
 Plus, LinkedIn and Instagram for the campuses across the globe by creating online campaigns for promotion and
 generating leads.
- Migrating Database Systems, Student Application System and Learning Management System from in house Data centre to AWS and Office 365.

→ FREELANCE (MAY 2011 - PRESENT)

DESIGNATION: FREELANCER DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER

- Shouldered responsibility of architecting, developing, and improving web applications for all clients and fruitfully delivered more than 100 projects to date and served 60 plus clients.
- Excelled in rapid application development and management of technological issues for assigned projects, earning the highest customer satisfaction rating for all solutions delivered.
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for front end public and internal websites as well as challenging back-end server code.
- Experimented with a variety of languages and frameworks.
- Successfully offered technology consultation and helped clients in setting up the IT infrastructure, designed and developed responsive websites for small and medium-sized organisations.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONTINUED.

→ TORUS LABS (APRIL 2019 - JULY 2019)

DESIGNATION: CONTRACT FRONT END DESIGNER

- Proactively developed technical and business requirements and delivered intuitive and user-centered solutions.
- Pivotal in identifying, troubleshooting UX problems, making layout adjustments based on user feedback.
- Strong know-how in creating user journeys, personas, wire-frames, storyboards, user flows, process flows and site maps, developing UI mock-ups and prototypes on Adobe XD that clearly illustrate how the product function and look like.
- Successfully created a working prototype on Vue.js using HTML, CSS/SCSS, Javascript and Node.JS.

→ STUDY SMART OVERSEAS EDUCATION (OCTOBER 2014 - NOVEMBER 2016)

DESIGNATION: WEB DEVELOPER

- Participate in all phases of the development cycle including requirements analysis, design, test, implementation, maintenance and debugging.
- Created and maintained the Student Management System and Study Portal for IELTS, Design prototypes for Website and Web Applications.
- Spearheaded the design of necessary Landing Pages and Social Media adverts for Digital Marketing.
- · Handled the Updates & Maintenance all the Social Media Platforms like Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn & Instagram.

INTERNSHIPS AND CERTIFICATES

→ INTERN AT SAMTECH INFONET LIMITED (JANUARY 2013 - MAY 2013)

Worked with the Government of Rajasthan on the project "Social Justice Management System".

→ INTERN AT CROSS SECTION INTERACTIVE (JUNE 2010 - JULY 2010)

Created applications such as Invoicing System and Content Management Systems.

→ INTERN AT INFOGAIN INDIA PVT LTD (JUNE 2009 - JULY 2009)

Created website wire-frames, and researched and gathered client requirements. Created a web-based form designer using JQuery and Java.

CERTIFICATION IN WEBSITE DESIGNING AT F-TEC COMPUTER EDUCATION (MAY 2008)

Learned about Web technologies; JavaScript; HTML; Cascading Style Sheets; and Social Media and Macromedia Products.

EDUCATION.

BRUNEL UNIVERSITY, LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM (SEPTEMBER 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2017)

COURSE: MSC IN DIGITAL DESIGN AND BRANDING (MERIT)

- Developed a strategic approach to branding and its links to digital media and organisational performance.
- Evaluated the current state of the relationship between branding and digital design; and digital promotion and management.
- The main modules were Brand Experience Design; Digital Design; Digital Media Technologies; and Multimedia Research Directions.

GURU GOBIND SINGH INDRAPRASTHA UNIVERSITY, DELHI, INDIA (AUGUST 2010 - JULY 2013)

COURSE: MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATION (MCA) - CPI 73.50

- Equivalent to Masters in Software Engineering.
- It emphasises on planning; designing and building of complex commercial application software; and system software.
- Studied advanced level Mathematics; Programming Languages; Software and Web Development; and Database Management System.

→ GURU GOBIND SINGH INDRAPRASTHA UNIVERSITY, DELHI, INDIA (AUGUST 2007 - JULY 2010)

COURSE: BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATION (BCA) - CPI 73.20

• Studied Financial Management; Accounting; Mathematics; and Programming Languages such as C, Java, ASP.Net, Web Development, Database Management System, and so on.

→ CAMBRIDGE SCHOOL, DELHI, INDIA

COURSE: SENIOR(12TH) [2005] AND SECONDARY(10TH) [2007] SCHOOL EXAMINATION (CBSE)

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS.

- → Won 21 1st place awards in Software and Web Application Development; Graphics and Website Design throughout different competitions in India. The top awarding institutions are as follows:
 - Jawaharlal Nehru University, Delhi, India
 - Delhi College of Engineering, Delhi, India
 - Delhi University North and South Campus, Delhi, India
 - Amity University, Noida, India

- Indra Gandhi Institute of Technology, Delhi, India
- · University School of Information and Technology, Delhi,
- Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, Delhi, India
- Bharati Vidyapeeth Delhi, India

A FEW PROJECTS.

▶ PORTAL OF LONDON SCHOOL OF COMMERCE GROUP OF COLLEGES

Technologies used: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Typescript/JavaScript and SCSS

A global platform for admissions used in London, Manchester, Birmingham, Milton Keynes, Malta, Colombo, and Malaysia. I handled the software side of the project which was hosted on AWS Elastic Beanstalk. The system is used by prospective student, agents and marketing officers across the globe.

■ ASSESSMENT SYSTEM & ENGLISH TEST SYSTEM FOR ONLINE ASSESSMENTS WITH PROCTORING

Technologies used: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Typescript/JavaScript and SCSS

This is an Online platform for conducting assessments and English tests. It also has a proctoring mechanism, which confirms a student's identity and monitors him/her through a webcam.

→ REGISTRATION, APPOINTMENT, INTERVIEW AND PRE-QUALIFYING ASSESSMENT SYSTEM

Technologies used: Typescript/JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, SCSS, ExpressJS, MaterialUI, and Airtable API In this pandemic, I have created a full-fledged online process for the admissions department. The process has four different phases which are registration, appointment, interview feedback and pre-qualifying programme portal. The system is fully automated and currently used by all LSC UK campuses in London, Manchester, Birmingham and Milton Keynes.

ONLINE PORTAL FOR INDIA DEVELOPMENT FOUNDATION OF OVERSEAS INDIANS (MINISTRY OF EXTERNAL AFFAIRS)

Technologies used: PHP, MySql, ASP.NET, NIC Cloud and Customised Content Management System.

IDF-OI is a not-for-profit Trust set up by the Government of India to facilitate philanthropic contributions by overseas Indians to social and development projects in India. I single-handedly created the portal to receive online payments fro the overseas Indians. It was a 12-month project and hosted on NIC Government Cloud. All the necessary security measures and audits were done before the portal was made Live. Mrs Sushma Swaraj, External Affairs Minister of India inaugurated the portal in August 2016. It's one of the biggest achievements for me.

→ VIRTUAL CLASSROOMS AND GLOBAL STUDENT ACCESS PORTAL

Technologies used: Python, ExpressJS, NodeJS and AWS Lambda

In this pandemic, I have created a full-fledged Online process for the academics department. The process has four steps which are managing the timetable, creating and sending Zoom links and reminders to the students, automated attendance and assessment system. The system is fully automated and currently used by all LSC campuses in London, Bangladesh, Sri-Lanka, Malta and Malaysia.

→ GLOBAL ACCOUNTS PORTAL

Technologies used: PHP, MySql, Bootstrap and Elastic Beanstalk

Global accounts portal is a one-stop portal for all the student account activities happening in the organisation. More than 30 Accountants use this portal to manage the account details of around 30,000 students. It also helps in managing the fees of all the students who are studying at all the global campuses. The first version of the portal was designed in Visual Basics in 2003 which I have upgraded and migrated to AWS Elastic Beanstalk and RDS.

→ MOODLE INTEGRATION WITH STUDENT MANAGEMENT, ASSESSMENT AND ATTENDANCE SYSTEM

Technologies used: PHP, MySql, Elastic Beanstalk and Bootstrap

Created a plugin for the Moodle platform which fetches the student details and created Moodle user accounts. The plugin also fetches the attendance and the result from different databased and show it to the students when they log in.

Q REFERENCES.

Employment Reference #1

Name: Stephanie Bailey (hr@lsclondon.co.uk)

Designation: Human Resource Manager

Organisation: London School of Commerce, London

Employment Reference #2

Name: Chetan Jain (chetan@studysmart.co.in)

Designation: Founder and CEO

Organisation: Study Smart Overseas Education

Employment Reference #3

Name: Leonard Tan (leonard@tor.us)
Designation: Co-founder & CTO

Organisation: Torus Labs

Academic Reference

Name: Vanja Garaj (vanja.garaj@brunel.ac.uk)
Designation: Senior Lecturer in Digital Design
Organisation: Brunel University, London

Reference #1

Name: Benny Abraham (kblabraham@gmail.com)

Organisation: University of Wales Trinity Saint David

Designation: Director of Global Recruitment

Reference #2

Name: Leon Menezes (leonmenezes9@gmail.com)

Designation: IT Manager

Organisation: Procurement Leaders